A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 7, Accession 7 FA1189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- America-China Society / America-China Forum Programs and Staff, 1986-2002; 13
  - Directors Correspondence, Edmund S. Muskie, 1994-1996 (Box 53, Folder 508)
  - Directors Correspondence, I. M. Pei, 1989, 1994-2000 (Box 53, Folder 509)
  - Directors Correspondence, Abraham Ribicoff, 1994-1996 (Box 53, Folder 510)
  - Directors Correspondence, David Rockefeller, 1990-1999 (Box 53, Folder 511)
  - Directors Correspondence, William P. Rogers, 1992, 1995-1997 (Box 54, Folder 512)
  - Directors Correspondence, Bryan K. Sanderson (BP Amoco), 1999-2000 (Box 54, Folder 513)
  - Directors Correspondence, Brent Scowcroft, 1993-1995 (Box 54, Folder 514)
  - Directors Correspondence, Raymond P. Shafer, 1994-1995 (Box 54, Folder 515)
  - Directors Correspondence, Robert B. Shapiro (Monsanto), 1995-1998 (Box 54, Folder 516)
  - Directors Correspondence, George P. Shultz, 1989, 1995-1997 (Box 54, Folder 517)
  - Directors Correspondence, John R. (Jack) Stafford, 1995-1999 (Box 54, Folder 518)
  - Directors Correspondence, Harry C. Stonecipher (McDonnell Douglas), 1995-1999 (Box 54, Folder 519)
  - Directors Correspondence, Lawrason Thomas (AMOCO), 1993-1996 (Box 54, Folder 520)
  - Directors Correspondence, Alex Trotman (Ford), 1994-1999 (Box 54, Folder 521)
  - Directors Correspondence, Cyrus R. Vance, 1992-1999, 2002 (Box 54, Folder 522-523)
    Includes Cyrus Vance obituary (d. 2002 January 12) and eulogy by Henry Kissinger.
  - Directors Correspondence, Henry D.G. Wallace (Ford), 1999 (Box 54, Folder 524)
  - Directors Correspondence, John Whitehead, 1989-1999 (Box 54, Folder 525)
  - Directors Correspondence, Leonard Woodcock, 1990-2000 (Box 54, Folder 526)
  - America - China Society Negatives, circa 1990-1992, undated; Still Images: Black-and-white and color 35 mm negative strips. (Box 54, Folder 527-528)
    Meeting at Century Club, 1990 July 25 (2 pages of negatives). Board and Discussion Meeting, 1991 January 15-16 (12 pages). (Shanghai Communique 20th Anniversary Commemoration, Huang Ju Luncheon), 1992 April 29 (4 pages). Roundtable Discussion Meeting, 1992 December 15 (4 sets of negatives) (see also Contact Sheets). Unidentified ACS event: 7 sets of undated color negative strips, labeled A-G.
  - America - China Society Roundtable Discussion Meeting (Photographs), 1992 December 15; Still Images: Four black and white 11 x 14 contact sheets. (Box 59, Folder 529)
    Contact sheets with images of the event. Attribution taken from label on corresponding negatives (in box 54, folders 527-528).
  - Executive Director Chronological Files and Memos - Restricted Material from boxes 23-28, 1993-1999 (Box 58, Folder 571)
    Restricted - Personnel material
    Confidential records (personnel records) removed from Box 23, folders 215, 218. box 25, folders 232-233. box 26, folders 237-238, 241. box 28, folder 250. and box 29, folders 256-257.
  - Individual Correspondence and Contacts - Restricted Material from boxes 37 - 39, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 572)
    Restricted - Confidential material
    Confidential records (mainly personnel records) removed from Box 37, folders 337, 342, 343, 344. Box 38, folder 347 (graduate school application and evaluation). Box 39, folder 353.
  - David M. Albert - Restricted Material from Box 50, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 573)
    Restricted - Personnel material.
    Confidential material removed from Box 50, folder 465.
  - Directors Correspondence, Herbert J. Hansell - Restricted Material from Box 52, 1994 (Box 58, Folder 574)
    Restricted - personnel material
    Confidential records (personnel records) removed from Box 52, folder 497. Records concern Herbert Levin, and Nancy Grunthal.
  - Directors Correspondence, Herbert J. Hansell - Restricted Material from Box 53, folders 498-499., 1995-1996 (Box 58, Folder 575-576)
    Confidential records (personnel records) removed from Box 53, folders 498-499. Records concern Herbert Levin, Nancy Grunthal, and Donna Dayton.
  - Recommendations: Gomez, Milena, 1996 (Box 58, Folder 577)
    Letter of recommendation from Herbert Levin.
  - Recommendations: Kaihara, Hiroshi, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 578)
    Restricted - Confidential Material
    Graduate school applications and letter of recommendation by Herbert Levin. File includes academic transcripts.
- Clippings and Reference, 1957-2014; 15
  The Clippings and Reference series in RG 7 contains publications on a variety of topics relating to China, from the 1950s to the present. In addition to writings on Communist China in the mid-1960s, the series significantly includes a Clippings Book on the Harvard University Journalists' Seminar, July 13-15, 1967.
  - Surveys on Perceptions of Asia and China (General), 1995-2010 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Mixed Messages: A Survey of the Foreign Policy Views of American Leaders, 1995. Soft Power in Asia (Survey of Public Opinion), 2009. Image: Acknowledgement and Expectation. Report of the Survey on Chinese National Status in the Eyes of the Chinese Public and the Foreigners, 2010.
  - Committee of 100 Surveys, 2001, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    American Attitudes toward Chinese Americans and Asian Americans, 2001. US China Public Perceptions, Opinion Survey, 2012.
  - Coverage of the United States in Key Chinese Periodicals during 1984 (David L. Shambaugh), 1985 December (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Random Notes on Red China, 1936-1945 (Edgar Snow), 1957, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Sino-Soviet Dispute, 1956-63: Extracts from Recent Documents, 1964 February (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Ed. John Gittings. Chatham House Memoranda.
  - General Study of the Channels of Communication between Communist China and the Western World (Vincent V. S. King), 1964 May (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Propaganda Campaigns in Communist China (Vincent V. S. King), 1966 January (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Peking and the Latin American Communists (Ernst Halperin), 1966 November (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - China (General), 1965 -1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Morton H. Halperin, Is China Turning In (December 1965) and China and Nuclear Proliferation (1966). The China Puzzle, League of Women Voters, 1967. John G. Stoessinger, "The Coming of Communism to China" (1967 September). Nicholas Katzenbach, Communist China: A Realistic View, 1968 May 21. Russia, China and the West, British Information Services, 1968.
  - China (General), 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Campaign for Normalization of US - China Diplomatic Relations: A Handbook, US-China People's Friendship Association (1976). Harry Harding, Jr., China and the U.S.: Normalization and Beyond (1979). English Language Test Used by the People's Republic of China in Selecting Candidtates for Study Abroad in 1978-1979. Contemporary China (1977 May). New China (1979 Fall and Winter).
  - China (General), 1984-1997 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Includes Michel Oksenberg, President Reagan's China Trip: A Background Paper (1984 April). A. Doak Barnett, After Deng, What. Will China Follow the USSR (1991). Thomas W. Robinson, "Chinese Foreign Policy Post-Tiananmen" (1994 May).
  - China (General), 1990s (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
    General background reading. Offprints and copies of articles and papers. Includes "Policy Impact Panel on the Future of U.S.-China Relations" (1994), with Jan Berris notes. Kenneth Lieberthal paper on "The Future of United States - China Relations: A Proposal for a Sustainable, Bipartisan Policy" (1994). NBR Analysis, The Future of China (1992 August).
  - China (General), 1987, 1995-2007, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
    Includes Congressional Research Service Report, "China-US Relations: Current Issues and Implications for US Policy" (2007 February 14). Donald Zagoria, U.S. - China and Cross-Straight Relations: How Stable (2011).
  - Publications on China (General), 1978-2014 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Our Next Five Years. The Agenda for Hong Kong, Address by Governor Christopher Patten, 1992 October 7. Britain-China (Winter 1992-1993). China Rising, SAISPHERE (2006). U. S. - China Perception Monitor, 2014 January 22.
  - Covering China (Media Studies Journal), 1999 Winter (Box 4, Folder 41)
    Volume 13, number 1.
  - Education In China, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - State-of-the-Environment Profile for the People's Republic of China, 1979 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    By Susan Swannack-Nunn, with Kenneth I. Bowman and Pat Heffernan. Prepared by the National Council for US - China Trade for the Environmental Protection Agency.
  - Powering China: The Environmental Implications of China's Economic Development (Draft), 1995 February 18 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Study by Daniel C. Esty and Robert Mendelsohn, with Daniel H. Rosen and Therese Feng.
  - Vietnam (Bibliography and Readings), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Clippings Book: Press Conference, June 6, 1967, and Journalists' Seminar, Harvard University, July 13-15, 1967, 1967 June-July (Box 17, Folder 164)
- Sister Cities, 1979-1998; 16
  This series contains correspondence, agreements, and promotional materials relating to the establishment of "Sister" relationships between U. S. states and cities and their Chinese counterparts, from the late 1970s to the mid-1990s. The National Committee appears to have had little active involvement in the program.
  - Sister Cities: General, 1983-1998 (Box 55, Folder 530)
  - National Council on U.S. - China Sister State and City Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 55, Folder 531)
  - National Council on U. S. - China Sister State and City Relations, 1985-1986; Floppy disk, 5 1/4 inch. (Box 55, Folder 531)
    Content unidentified (label on disk is illegible).
  - Sister Cities International, 1980-1997 (Box 55, Folder 532)
  - Sister City - State Conference, 1984 August 3-5 (Box 55, Folder 533-534)
    Cosponsored by the Mershon Center, Ohio State University. Includes conference reports, notes, and correspondence.
  - Canadian Conference on Province / State Affiliations with China, 1986 March 10-11 (Box 55, Folder 535)
    Jan Berris attended.
  - Conference on U. S. - China State and City Relationships, 1986 June 20-22 (Box 55, Folder 536)
    Sister Cities conference.
  - U. S. - China Sister City - State Agreements, circa 1985-1986 (Box 55, Folder 537-538)
  - China Sister Relations with Other Countries, 1979-1988 (Box 56, Folder 539)
  - Alaska - Heilongjiang Sister Relations, 1985-1988 (Box 56, Folder 540)
  - Baltimore - Xiamen Sister Relations, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 541)
  - Boulder - Lhasa Sister City Project, 1987-1988 (Box 56, Folder 542)
  - Alberta - Heilongjiang Sister Relations, 1984-1991; Realia: File includes 3 commemorative lapel pins (Edmonton - Harbin, 1985; Heilongjiang - Alberta; Alberta). (Box 56, Folder 543)
    Edmonton - Harbin sister cities.
  - Alberta - Heilongjiang Sister Relations, 1984-1991; Oversized newsletter publication, variously sized 12"x 15" - 11"x 17". (Box 59)
    Asia - Alberta Exchange newsletter, 1984-1988, 1991 (18 issues).
    Separated from Series 16, Box 56, folder 543.
  - Ontario - Jiangsu Sister Relations, 1985-1987 (Box 56, Folder 544)
  - Connecticut - Shandong Sister Relations, 1983-1987 (Box 56, Folder 545)
  - Colorado - Hunan and Denver - Kunming Sister Relations, 1984-1995 (Box 56, Folder 546)
  - Galveston - Sanya Sister Relations, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 547)
    One item.
  - Harrisburg-Luoyang Sister Relations, Undated (Box 56, Folder 548)
    Undated protocol.
  - Iowa-Hebei Sister Relations, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 549)
  - Illinois - Liaoning Sister Relations, 1982-1992 (Box 56, Folder 550)
  - Jacksonville - Yingkou sister city relations, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 551)
  - Kansas - Henan Sister Relations, 1979-1985, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 552)
    Includes Wichita - Kaifeng City sister relations, 1985, 1997.
  - Los Angeles-Guangzhou Sister Relations, 1980-1983, 1994-1998 (Box 56, Folder 553)
  - Maryland - Anhui Sister Relations, 1979-1981, 1992-1993 (Box 56, Folder 554)
  - Massachusetts - Guangdong Sister Relations, 1982-1983, 1993-1994 (Box 56, Folder 555)
  - Michigan - Sichuan Sister Relations, 1982-1987 (Box 56, Folder 556)
  - New Jersey - Zhejiang Sister Relations, 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 557)
  - New York City - Beijing Sister Relations (Correspondence), 1980-1992 (Box 57, Folder 558 -559)
    Includes correspondence in response to the events of Tiananmen, 1989. catalogue from Beijing-New York exhibit, Snug Harbor Cultural Center, 1988.
  - New York City - Beijing and New York State - Jiangsu Sister Relations, 1980-1989 (Box 57, Folder 560)
    Includes loan of pandas from the Beijing Zoo, 1987.
  - North Carolina - Liaoning Sister Relations, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 561)
    File contains Liaoning chamber of commerce newsletter. Illinois was also a sister with Liaoning.
  - Oakland - Dalian Sister Relations, 1985-1993 (Box 57, Folder 562)
  - Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon Sister Relations, 1980-1981 (Box 57, Folder 563)
    Ohio - Hubei Province, 1980-1984. Oklahoma - Gansu Province, 1984, and Oklahoma City - Haikou. Oregon - Fujian Province, 1984-1991.
  - Philadelphia - Tianjin and Portland, OR - Suzhou Sister Relations, 1980-1991 (Box 57, Folder 564)
  - St. Louis - Nanjing Sister Relations, 1979-1991 (Box 57, Folder 565)
    Includes NCUSCR luncheon in New York in honor of Xu Yingrui and Nanjing Municipal Delegation, 1986 June 27.
  - San Francisco - Shanghai Sister Relations, 1979-1995 (Box 57, Folder 566)
  - Southern States - Kentucky and Virginia, 1979-1985 (Box 57, Folder 567)
    Kentucky - Jiangxi Province, 1985. Virginia trade delegation, 1979.
  - Washington State - Sichuan Province and Seattle - Chongqing Sister Relations, 1982-1988, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 568)
  - Washington, DC, Wilmington, Wisconsin Sister Relations, 1982-1987 (Box 57, Folder 569)
    Washington, DC - Beijing, 1985. Wilmington - Dandong, 1987. Wisconsin - Heilongjiang Province, 1982.